念能力は 次の６つの系統に分類される
Your technique has two huge weaknesses!
[TV]　オークションの開催まで あと１か月あるが
Jajanken... I understand.
それまでに　これから渡す リストの中から１つ
You combined "jajan" for "ta-dah," with
"janken" for your attack, "Rock-Paper-Scissors."
どれでもいいから探して来てくれ。
Ah, no...
[TV]　それをクリアすれば
Not a bad name, kid!
正式に契約し 護衛と収集活動を担ってもらう。
Uh, yeah. Guess I'm okay with that. You are?! Gon, your Jajanken has two huge weaknesses.
それが　現在の私と 依頼主との距離
First, it takes too long to charge.
この距離を 限りなくゼロにする
During a fight, you don't have time
to stand still for several seconds.
相手が気を許し　秘密の共有をも 求めて来るほどに
I wouldn't count on having the time to charge it.
必ず探し出す
I know that.
まずは取り入る 信頼を得るために
Second, it's too risky.
ん？　開かねえぜ？ [TV]　１つ　言い忘れたが
When you focus aura in your
fist to increase power, you have less aura for defense. One attack to the wrong place
will take you out, fool!
強いことが雇用の最低条件だ。 [TV]　その館から 無事　出られるくらい
I know the risks. That's why I've spent the past month
training to compensate for them!
驚いたな 鎖で弾を止めるとは
I can tell which area you're defending. I can see what you're trying to do.
フッ！ 銃が３人
So if I use that information to fake you out, shifting your intended point of attack...
フン！ お前ら殺気を消すのは見事だが
This is the result!
実のとこ　腕は大したことねえな。
Damn...
これならば　「念」を 繰り出すまでもねえ！
His aura is giving away his every move!
なるほどな　そういうことか 分かったぜ
Okay, then... Time to throw a real punch.
奴らを止めろ。
First, it takes too long to charge.
３秒待つ　１・２…。
He's teaching me when he doesn't have to...
ＯＫ　分かったよ！
And providing guidance. He's telling me how to become stronger.
あ…。 こ…　これは…。 やはり　「念」。
He's too gentle!
人の形をしたオーラの塊だってな。 だが　そいつの「念」とは 気づかなかった。
First comes rock...
ほう…。
I told you that you won't pull off that attack.
違和感に気づいた　きっかけは
Don't fool around with me!
２階に現れた攻撃者だ。 奴らは私が シャンデリアに飛び移った後も
That was your full strength?
お粗末なことに　階下へは行かず
Which one of us is fooling around?!
届かぬ私に向かって 剣を振り続けた。
It's supposed to be a serious fight!
恐らく こう命じられていたのだろう。
You should be fighting to kill, Knuckle!
「一番近い敵を攻撃しろ」。 え…。 単純な命令しか与えられず その攻撃技術も未熟。
First comes rock...
１１体も遠距離操作で動かす パワーを持つ能力者。
Here I go! Rock...
そいつは十中八九 放出系に属する念能力者。 駆使するオーラの 大きさから考えて
Over here!
つまり能力者は… この部屋の中にいることになる。
First comes rock... Rock...
館の主人に雇われている まぁ　いわば君達の先輩だ。
Bastard...
分かったら ナイフを収めてくれねえか？
He faked me out with his Jajanken.
その鎖…
Even I could tell exactly when your
right arm was going to strike.
どうやら　あんた 操作系の能力者らしいなぁ。
He's using Jajanken's weakness, the long
charge time, against his opponent.
まぁ　悪く思わないでくれ。
He's playing mind games.
俺も　ボスに命令されて やったんだ。 「殺すつもりで試せ」ってなぁ。
Knuckle sees Gon's Jajanken as an easy pitch.
しかし　こんなに早くバレるとは 思わなかったぜ。
He has to swing for it.
まっ　君達４人の力なら 館から脱出できるだろう。
It's a perfect pitch, right down the
middle, that he has to send flying. That's the trigger.
頑張りな。 ４人？
When you see the easy ball, you tense up.
もう１人　この中に 交ざってやがるのか…。
You can hit it. You have to.
フフっ。
These thoughts make you use
more strength than necessary.
恐らくは　かく乱のつもりで 言ったのだろうが　失言だったな。 えっ？ お互いに疑心暗鬼になる前に…
The same thing applies to aura. If a Nen user doesn't control their aura, it will gather in areas of tension. The moment of the swing, it intensifies further.
私が他に　潜入者がいるかどうかを 調べよう。
If the Nen user is inexperienced or out of control, the aura will either stagnate
or just flow too freely.
あっ！ えっ？ いたな。
The fake-out will be more believable, and if the enemy steps back, they're easier to hit with Scissors or Paper.
お前が潜入者だ。
would be less useful once opponents
figured out how it works.
バ…　バカな！ 何を根拠に言ってるんだ！
Okay, let's try this again. In the second attempt, he was
too focused on the technique
ただ　鎖が揺れただけじゃないか。
and let Knuckle land a kick on him.
ダウジングってやつよ。 はぁ？　何だ　そりゃ！
But if he learns to better control his aura
in response to the opponent's movement, it will be harder to distinguish between
地下の水脈や鉱脈を 探索するための技術なんだけど 古くは 占いにも利用されていたし
fake and real Jajanken attempts. Gon's been thinking how to shore
up his technique's weaknesses.
ウソを見破るために用いられる とも聞いたことがあるわ。
No...
だからといって 俺が潜入者だという
He thought of the solution during this fight.
確実な証拠には ならねえだろうが！ 恐らく当たっているわ。
He's making incredible progress while fighting.
あなた　指さされた時 心臓が　すごい音で鳴ったもの。 もし　ぬれぎぬなら
I'm already getting tired.
じわじわと 心臓の音が大きくなるのよ
We haven't even been
fighting for twenty minutes.
誤解による不安と興奮でね。
Moving so much is sapping my energy.
でも　あなたは 初めが一番大きくて 音色が　どんどん静かに 落ち着いて行った。
If an hour of training is comparable
to ten minutes of fighting, I'll only be able to maintain my Ken for another ten minutes.
典型的なウソつきの旋律なのよ
If my aura defense goes down, I'm finished.
あなた達　２人とも。
Before then, I have to end this. By using Jajanken.
２人が　お前だと言っている。 残った５人のうち　２人もだぜ？
Bring it!
潜入者が２人かもしれないだろ？ ちなみに　彼も潜入者ではない。
Knuckle definitely has superior physical strength. But Gon is adapting, little by little.
失礼ね 「彼」じゃなくて「彼女」よ。 ウフ　あなたも違うわね。
By increasing the area his aura covers, he reduces the damage from miscalculations.
だから　それが信用できねえって 言ってんだよ！
And he's getting used to Knuckle's speed.
お前ら２人で口裏合わせて ってことも　あり得る。
Sudden punches almost never hit him anymore.
フン。
But he's running out of time.
うっ！　と…　とにかく 時間の無駄だぜ。
He doesn't have much stamina
left to maintain his aura.
ここで　うだうだやってたって 結論なんか出やしないぜ。
On the other hand, Knuckle has
been conserving his strength, only attacking with physical blows.
フン　「しょうがねえ 俺が結論　出してやる」。
Jajanken requires a large
amount of aura just to charge.
「オレ様が　殴ったモノは みな燃える」。
They started fighting twenty minutes ago.
はぁ？
If he uses Jajanken again,
he'll only have a minute or two
これが俺の力 「グレイトハイカー」！
to fight at full strength.
「クソったれ 燃えが今イチ　駄作だぜ」。 え？
You told me to use my full strength, but you're no match for me right now.
ちなみに　こいつは 俳句というもので
You're...
俺の祖国が誇る文学だ。
First comes
俺が詠み記した句は　実現する。
rock...
説明終わり　ここからが本題だ。
What... is he going to do?
「我が問いに 空言人が　焼かれ死ぬ」。
First comes
「ウソつきは 灼熱地獄に　落ちるわよ」
rock...
違う。 あんたか？ 違うわよ。
He isn't even going to hit Knuckle.
あんたか？ 違うわ。
This is definitely Gon's final attack.
あんたは潜入者か？ ああ　そうだ。
This will end it. Rock... Scissors... Paper!
お前は潜入者か？ さぁ　返答を！
An Emitter attack? But it's much weaker than his Rock.
はぁ…　答えは「イエス」だ。
He can't have any more tricks up his sleeve. Once I knock that aside, it's over!
お見事　ご褒美に教えてやるよ。
Once again! Once again?
俺は　スクワラ 正式なライセンスは持ってないが
He used that ball as cover
to move behind me? Crap!
操作系に属する能力を持っている ハンターだ。
Two Jajankens in a row...
その力を使って　すでに ある命令を念じてある。
Rock!
これが私の力 「インスタント　ラヴァー」。 私も操作系の能力者。
Otherwise, I'd be the one on the ground...
ハァハァ… ご　ご　ご…　ご主人様！
Where are you going, fool? I'm going back.
ハァハァ…。
Aren't you going to fight? I'm fine here.
ほらほら　ほらほら ほらほら！
You can fight Gon again tomorrow.
あ！　もっと　もっと お踏みくださいませ！
The outcome will probably be different. I'll defeat Shoot.
さぁ　早く答えて！
Tell Gon this.
何に　どんな「念」を込めたか 言ってごらん。
Tomorrow, I'll be fighting for real.
ほら　さぁ！　言わなきゃ 踏むのをやめるわよ！
He'd better be prepared to die.
私は卑しい　卑しい 犬使いなのです！
It sounds like you're trying to convince yourself. Sure you're up to the task?
何て… おっかねえ能力だ
Hell, yeah, fool. Tomorrow...
館の中には 私が「念」を込めた さまざまな犬が放たれています。
As long as you win, it's fine if you don't get serious.
例えば　マルチーズ。 相手の足に　まとわりつき 動きを鈍らせます。 そこへ　セント・バーナードが 巨体を生かして
But if you lose without fighting at full strength, I won't forgive you.
上から覆いかぶさり 動きを止めます。 間髪を入れずに　ドーベルマンが 一斉に襲いかかり
I'll never forgive you, as long as I live.
もう　いいから！ 早く犬にかけた「念」を解きな！ は　はい！
You're still soft.
「犬使い　自分がペットに なりにけり」か。
If you don't want to go to NGL,
hand over your token to them. Though I'm sure that they'll refuse it.
やめてよ　あれは 吐かせるために　やったこと。
Bastard...
ペットにするなら もっと上等な男を選ぶわよ！
You're pretty cocky when you aren't
shaking in your boots, eh?
そういえば まだ名前を聞いてなかったな。
The past month, all you've done is stalk them!
俺はバショウ　さっき見た通り 具現化系の能力者だ。 私はヴェーゼ。 センリツよ。
I'll fight. Tomorrow, I'll join the fight.
あなたは？
I gave him a massage, so he'll be able to fight in top condition tomorrow.
知りたいわ　あなたの名前… 教えてくれる？
Killua's the real issue... I wasn't expecting him to go
断る。 まだ仲間になると 決まったわけじゃ　ない。
the whole month without fighting once.
まぁ　そうだな　館を出るという 第１関門は突破したが 本番は　これからだ。
Fight me.
仕事にありつけないわけだしね…。
Huh?
嫌でも　また会うことになる ってわけだ…。
What happened to your face, Killua?! Huh? I was training with Bisky.
どうだ？　奴らは。
Anyway, are you feeling okay?
今回の４人は 使えると思いますよ。
Yep, I feel great.
少なくとも　奴よりは。
I used up all my aura, so I expected
to be tired, but look!
フン…　とりあえず 奴に用は　ない。 額に入れて飾っておけ。
That gorill— That old hag's massage must have done the trick.
任せたぞ　スクワラ。
That was close.
は…　はい。
Listen now... If you tell anyone what happened yesterday, I'll make your face three times worse.
品を手に入れ　契約を結べば
Now, do you know your weakness?
ヨークシンで開かれる オークション会場へ行くことができる
You're too quick to give up.
いや　何としても 行かねばならない！
You're too cautious about fighting.
そこには「幻影旅団」が…
Some might say you underestimate yourself.
私の同胞　クルタ族を 皆殺しにした盗賊団も 必ず現れる
When facing an enemy you
believe to be stronger, you fight on the premise of escaping.
燃えるような　深い緋色に輝く 我々の瞳
I realize that this isn't your fault.
世界７大美色に数えられる それを手に入れるために 殺戮の限りを尽くした奴らを 私は決して許さない
It's the fault of whoever taught you to fight.
必ず捕らえて 一網打尽にしてみせる！
Habits that are burned into your
body and soul aren't easy to break.
ふん　これが 『グリードアイランド』。
If the conditions are right, A, B, and C all have the potential to defeat D.
キルが手に入れたっていう ロムカードの中身は
But in your case, you're assuming
どうやら本物らしいな。
the enemy is always at their best.
((兄貴なら このデータを解析して
You always assume the worst-case scenario.
ソフト自体　再生することも できるんじゃないの？)) できるさ　全部　丸裸にして クリアしてやる。
Even when facing enemies with equal strength, you worry about how strong they are,
or what they might do to you.
伝説を終わらせ　ついでに ５００億ジェニーの懸賞金も。
If we're talking about a stronger
enemy, there's no question...
おっと ギブ・アンド・テークだったな。
You don't bother to think of how you could win.
キルの奴に　ハンター専用サイトの アドレス　教えなきゃ。
Running is your only option.
That's how losers think.
約束破ったりしたら あいつ　また 俺の大事なフィギュアを
to face enemies stronger than
you will take determination.
ぶち壊すとか 言い出しかねないしな。
If you can't defeat Shoot tomorrow, you must leave Gon's side.
気が早えよ！　約束の日まで あと２週間もあるぜ。
Let's go.
そっか。
Yeah.
あの時は　まさか こんな目的のために ヨークシンへ来るとは 思ってなかったけどな。 ) )
Killua's overly cautious style is the
product of a smothering love.
((９月１日 ヨークシンシティで！)) オークションが始まる ９月１日までに
A twisted, self-serving love...
『グリードアイランド』の情報 集められるだけ集めねえとな。
That just makes his habits stronger,
deeper, and harder to break.
うん　その中に　ジンにつながる 情報もあるかもしれないし。
Without extraordinary willpower,
this curse cannot be broken.
その日　ヨークシンシティで開幕する オークションで
The loser...
彼らを待ち受けているのは 果たして…
Hands his token to the winner.